K SURYA PRAKASH  AI&DS Student
ksurya86609@gmail.com +91 8660922027 Bengaluru, Karnataka 560085 
ksuryaprakashportfolio.netlify.app/ github.com/surya27092004 
linkedin.com/in/sp-suryaprakash 
SUMMARY
I am K Surya Prakash, an aspiring Software Engineer currently pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Artificial 
Intelligence and Data Science. I have a strong interest in integrating technical expertise with creative problem-
solving. Skilled in Python, Java, and HTML, I thrive in collaborative environments and am committed to 
continuous learning. I actively seek opportunities to apply my knowledge through hands-on projects and 
internships to further enhance my professional skills.
EDUCATION
Bachelor of Engineering in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science, 
K S SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING AND MANAGEMENT
òCGPA: 8.502026 û 2026
Bengaluru, Karnataka
PUC in PCMC's, SRI KRISHNA PU COLLEGE
òPercentage: 742022 û 2022
Bengaluru, Karnataka
EXPERIENCE
Data Science Intern, Pinnacle Labs
òEngineered chatbot and fake news detection utilizing Python and datasets.07/2025 û 08/2025
Bengaluru, India
PROJECTS
ADAS and Pothole Detection
òAn ongoing project focused on improving road safety through technology.Al-
based detection system for potholes and driver assistance using real-time image 
analysis02/2025 û Present
ARTS - Aegis Rail Track Security
òA mini project designed to improve railway safety and monitoring.Conceptualized 
a system for monitoring rail tracks using sensor input and alert mechanisms07/2024 û 12/2024
LLM Corrector
òA project aimed at enhancing user interaction with AI models.Developed a tool to 
refine and correct user prompts using language model techniques and NLP 
concepts2024 û 2025
Chat Bot
òCreated a conversational agent with a focus on user experience.Developed a 
chatbot for basic interactions with emphasis on natural flow and response 
accuracy07/2025 û 08/2025
Fake News Detection
òA complete machine learning web application for detecting fake news using 
Python, Streamlit, and scikit-learn. The application uses natural language 
processing techniques to classify news articles and headlines as either Real or 
Fake.06/2025 û 07/2025---PAGE START---TECHNICAL SKILLS
Languages
HTML , CSS , Java , Java Script , Python , SQL , 
MongoDB 
AI/ML Concepts
NLP , Clustering AlgorithmsFrameworks & Tools
Numpy , Pandas , OpenCV , MatplotLib , Git , PowerBI 
, Figma , UI/UX
SOFT SKILLS
Project Management Public Relations Teamwork Time Management
Effective Communication Critical Thinking Adaptability
CERTIFICATIONS
Python Programming (Part 1, 2 
& Foundation), Onwingspan 
(Infosys SpringBoard)
Web Development with HTML, 
CSS, JS, DataFlair
Introduction to Python, 
DataFlair
Introduction to Java, DataFlair
Prompt Design in Vertex AI, 
Google CloudPython Foundation 
Certification, Onwingspan 
(Infosys SpringBoard)
Introduction to Pandas, 
Numpy, Matplotlib & OpenCV, 
DataFlair
Introduction to SQL,DataFlair
Introduction to Generative AI 
and Generative AI Studio, 
Google Cloud
Data Analytics Course, Google 
CloudApplied Artificial Intelligence: 
Practical Implementations, 
TechSaksham / Edunet 
Foundation
Introduction to Machine 
Learning, DataFlair
Introduction to DSA, DataFlair
Python Data Analytics, Mevi 
Technologies
LANGUAGES
English
First Language
Tamil
ManageableTelugu
Fluent
Hindi
ManageableKannada
Fluent
ACHIEVEMENTS
Regional Expo:
òPresented a LLM Corrector project at Regional Hub Expo at Hassan sponsored by TechSaksham/EduNet 
Foundation
SAP-HACKATHON
òParticipated in college level SAP-HACAKTHON
